<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="setup_comp.xsl" ?>

<definitions_variables> 

  <entry id="COMP_OCN"> 
    <type>char</type>
    <valid_values>docn</valid_values>
    <default_value>dlnd</default_value>
    <group>case_comp</group>
    <sdesc>Name of ocn component</sdesc>
  </entry>

  <entry id="DOCN_MODE"> 
    <type>char</type>
    <valid_values>prescribed,som,copyall,null</valid_values>
    <default_value>prescribed</default_value>
    <group>run_component_docn</group>
    <sdesc>DOCN mode</sdesc>
    <ldesc>
      The data ocean component (DOCN) always returns SSTs to the
      driver. The atmosphere/ocean fluxes are computed in the
      coupler. Therefore, the data ocean model does not compute fluxes like
      the data ice model. DOCN has two distinct modes of operation. It can
      arun as a pure data model, reading in ocean SSTs (normally
      climatological) from input datasets, performing time/spatial
      interpolations, and passing these to the coupler. Alternatively,
      DOCN can compute updated SSTs by running as a slab ocean model where
      bottom ocean heat flux convergence and boundary layer depths are read
      in and used with the atmosphere/ocean and ice/ocean fluxes obtained
      from the driver.
      --- A setting of prescribed assumes the only field in the input stream is SST.
      It also assumes the SST is in Celsius and must be converted to Kelvin.
      All other fields are set to zero except for ocean salinity, which
      is set to a constant reference salinity value.
      Normally the ice fraction data is found in the same data files that
      provide SST data to the data ocean model. They are normally found in
      the same file because the SST and ice fraction data are derived from
      the same observational data sets and are consistent with each other.
      to the data ocean model. They are normally found in the same file
      because the SST and ice fraction data are derived from the same
      observational data sets and are consistent with each other.
      --- A setting of som (slab ocean model) mode is a prognostic mode.  This mode
      computes a prognostic sea surface temperature and a freeze/melt
      potential (surface Q-flux) used by the sea ice model.  This
      calculation requires an external SOM forcing data file that includes
      ocean mixed layer depths and bottom-of-the-slab Q-fluxes.
      Scientifically appropriate bottom-of-the-slab Q-fluxes are normally
      ocean resolution dependent and are derived from the ocean model output
      of a fully coupled CCSM run.  Note that while this mode runs out of
      the box, the default SOM forcing file is not scientifically
      appropriate and is provided for testing and development purposes only.
      Users must create scientifically appropriate data for their particular
      application.  A tool is available to derive valid SOM forcing. 
      Default is prescribed.
    </ldesc>
    <values>
      <value compset="_DOCN%NULL">null</value>
      <value compset="_DOCN%DOM" >prescribed</value>
      <value compset="_DOCN%SOM" >som</value>
      <value compset="_DOCN%US20">us20</value>
      <value compset="_DOCN%COPY">copyall</value>
    </values>
  </entry>

  <entry id="DOCN_SOM_FILENAME">
    <type>char</type>
    <valid_values></valid_values>
    <default_value>UNSET</default_value>
    <group>run_component_docn</group>
    <sdesc>Sets SOM forcing data filename for pres runs, only used in D and E compset</sdesc>
    <ldesc>Sets SOM forcing data filename for pres runs, only used in D and E compset</ldesc>
    <values>
      <value compset="_DOCN%SOM.*_TEST" >pop_frc.1x1d.090130.nc</value>
    </values>
  </entry>

  <description>
    <desc compset="_DOCN%NULL">docn null mode:</desc>
    <desc compset="_DOCN%SOM" >docn slab ocean mode:</desc>
    <desc compset="_DOCN%DOM" >docn data mode:</desc>
    <desc compset="_DOCN%US20">docn us20 mode:</desc>
    <desc compset="_DOCN%COPY">docn copy mode:</desc>
  </description>

  <help>
    =========================================
    DOCN naming conventions
    =========================================
  </help>

</definitions_variables> 

